Sofia Rassin

Account Manager / Documentation Specialist / Logistics Coordinator

Feasterville, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Sofia-Rassin/140d2c218b8402e9

International Logistics experience as a Freight Forwarder, Importer and Exporter with 19 years of experience having worked both in the U.S. and in overseas offices.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

International Operations Logistics Coordinator

CHEMLOGIX/CLX Logistics, Inc. - Blue Bell, PA - March 2014 to Present

Responsibilities

Coordinating and handling export Chemical Shipments (Hazardous and Non Hazardous) worldwide, including ISO-Tanks from the time PO is received until the material and documentation are delivered to the customer overseas. Preparing booking confirmations, AES entry and authoring Master Bill of Lading Instructions; Proofing Bills of Lading with processing documentation corrections; Document distribution to necessary parties, agent/customer billing; Obtaining necessary information to process and complete export documentation under the letters of credit. Knowledge of every document (Commercial invoice, Certificate of origin, Packing and weight list, Insurance certificate, etc.). Verifying terms of credit, such as amount, insurance coverage and shipping conditions to determine compliance with established standards. U.S. import and export compliance knowledge.

DOT, IMDG and IATA Dangerous Goods trained and certified.

Account Manager/Documentation Specialist

5K Logistics, Inc - Warminster, PA - July 2007 to March 2014

Responsibilities:

- Freight Forwarding developed / guided new and existing import and export accounts in both the creating and processing of Letters of Credit, Commercial Invoices, Packing Lists, Certificates of Origin, ATA Carnets, Incoterms and other international documents when required;
- Pricing and Profit quoted/priced international shipments for air and ocean with positive margin contributions of anywhere from 10% to 25% pending on the type of service and complexities of executing the move;
- International Documentation prepared and submitted necessary documents to complete the Export/Import process with Ocean Carriers and Air Carriers, e.g. Dock Receipts, Shippers Letters of Instruction, Proforma Ocean Bill of Ladings, Proforma Air Waybills;
- Tracking & Tracing executed in house procedures to advise all clients on status updates of said shipments e.g. Departures, Arrivals and Final POD;
- Managed all requirements surrounding the U.S. Automated Export System (AES) and the Transportation Security Administration (TSA);
- Import handled Import shipments, coordinated customs clearance with Customs Brokers, arranged Customs Bonds; door delivery to Free Trade Zone (FTZ);
- Developed strong communications with our international partners, i.e. GLN (Global Logistics Network), which allowed us to provide and extend our worldwide service as well as increase new import and export business opportunities:
- Invoicing Customers Continual timely invoicing and follow up for both Receivables and Payables.

Import Specialist

M.A.R.N. Ltd, Tel Aviv, Israel - ביבא לת זוחמ ,ופי- ביבא לת - July 1994 to April 2007

Responsibilities:

- Executed all steps of import/export transactions starting from sending orders to suppliers, preparing all business correspondence with vendors, selection of and communicating with freight forwarders, customs brokers, trucking companies;
- Preparation of all necessary documentation for customs clearance; checking for the accuracy of the paperwork and completeness:
- Negotiated payment terms (e.g. advance payment, open account, Letter of Credit, deferred payment, cash against documents, etc.) and managed accounts payable through EDI system:
- Handled opening of Letters of Credit, securing Marine Insurance, Calculation of costs for duties/taxes per the Harmonized codes and other expenses levied on imported goods.

Research Engineer

Scientific Research Institute, Moscow, Russia - Mockba - January 1984 to March 1991

In laboratory and pilot plant environments, researched new technologies for mechanical spinning of cotton fiber, developed new types of textile spinning machines.

EDUCATION

International Trade Import & Export in International Trade College "MALAV"

Tel Aviv, Israel 1994 to 1994

MS

Engineering School for Textiles and Light Industry - Mockba 1982 to 1984

BS in Natural and Synthetic Fiber Process Technology

Engineering School for Textiles and Light Industry - Mockba 1978 to 1982

SKILLS

MS Office proficiency (Excel/ Word/ PPT/ Outlook). Practical knowledge of multi-modal rates and INCO terms. Quoting and Handling Oversized and Project Cargo as well as FCL/LCL/Cargo; Daily Customer Service and Overseas Communications; Researching and complying with Country Specific Regulations; Coordination of Hazardous Shipments and providing proper IMO Documentation; Preparation of Export Documentation; NVOCC Regulations; Letter of Credit Preparation and presenting to the Bank for negotiation; Billing customers per company structure; Familiarity with Export Packing Regulations for various Countries. (10+ years)

CERTIFICATIONS

DOT HAZARDOUS MATERIALS

August 2014

IATA Dangerous Goods

September 2014

IMO / IMDG Dangerous Goods

June 2015

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages: Professional English, Native Russian, Fluent Hebrew